The Rebel Warrior
Patton is a war, drama, history film directed by Franklin J. Schaffner.
"Patton" tells the tale of General George S.
Patton, famous tank commander of World War II.
The film begins with Patton's career in North Africa and progresses through
the invasion of Germany and the fall of the Third Reich.
Side plots also speak of Patton's numerous faults such his
temper and habit towards insubordination.
General George S. Patton Jr., played by George C. Scott.
General Omar N. Bradley, played by Karl Malden.
Captain Chester B. Hansen, played by Stephen Young.
Brigadier General Hobart Carver, played by Michael Strong.
General Bradley's Driver, played by Carey Loftin.
Moroccan Minister, played by Albert Dumortier.
Patton is a 1970 American epic biographical war film about U.S.
General George S.
Patton during World War II.
It stars George C.
Scott as Patton and Karl Malden as General Omar Bradley.
The film was directed by Franklin J.
Schaffner from a script by Francis Ford Coppola and Edmund H.
North, who based their screenplay on Patton: Ordeal and Triumph by
Ladislas Farago and Bradley's memoir, A Soldier's Story.
Patton grossed over $60 million against a budget of $12 million.
It won seven Academy Awards, including Best Picture, Best
Director and Best Original Screenplay.
Scott also won the Best Actor for his performance, though he declined the award.
The opening monologue, delivered by Scott as General Patton with an enormous American
flag behind him, remains an iconic and often quoted image in film.
In 2003, Patton was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically or aesthetically significant".
The Academy Film Archive also preserved Patton in 2003.
The film explores themes of general, steel helmet,
allies, world war ii, normandy, france.
The tone is emotional.